[
  {
    "question": "Grapes start out as ... During this phase their color is ...",
    "answer": "Grapes start out as flowers. During this phase their color is green."
  },
  {
    "question": "When grapes ripen they swell with ... and ... levels rise.",
    "answer": "When grapes ripen they swell with water and sugars levels rise."
  },
  {
    "question": "During ripening white grapes change to what color?",
    "answer": "Golden"
  },
  {
    "question": "During ripening black grapes change to what color?",
    "answer": "Purple"
  },
  {
    "question": "Black grapes contain ... which can make your mouth feel ...",
    "answer": "Contain tannins which makes your mouth feel dry"
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe what you need for alcoholic fermentation and what comes out",
    "answer": "Sugar + year → alcohol + carbon dioxide"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because grapes need both sunlight to ripen and colder temperatures to rest, what latitudes do they grow best in?",
    "answer": "-30 to -50"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do locations closer to the equator do to grape growing?",
    "answer": "Higher sugar and lower acidity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Germany and northern France and cooler or warmer climates to grow wine?",
    "answer": "Cooler"
  },
  {
    "question": "What grapes are commonly grown in cool climates?",
    "answer": "White grapes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What grapes are commonly grown in warm climates?",
    "answer": "Black grapes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the steps in making white wine",
    "answer": "Crushing, pressing, fermentation, maturation, bottling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the steps in making red wine",
    "answer": "Crushing, fermentation, draining, pressing, maturation, bottling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the steps in making rosé wine",
    "answer": "Crushing, fermentation, draining, second fermentation without skin, pressing, maturation, bottling"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 3 types of wine",
    "answer": "Still, sparking, fortified"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 3 styles of wine",
    "answer": "White, red, rosé"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the normal alcohol by volume (ABV) for still wine? And what is common?",
    "answer": "Between 8% and 15%. Most are between 11.5% and 14%."
  },
  {
    "question": "Many still wines are named after ...",
    "answer": "The region in which they’re produced"
  },
  {
    "question": "Still wines are less commonly named after ...",
    "answer": "The grape variety used to make them"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 3 examples of still wine types and the countries they’re from",
    "answer": "Burgundy and Sancerre from France. Rioja from Spain. Chianti from Italy."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fizz in sparkling wine is caused by ...",
    "answer": "The carbon dioxide gas that is produced by fermentation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 3 examples of sparkling wine types and the countries they’re from",
    "answer": "Champagne from France, Cava from Spain, and Prosecco from Italy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 3 examples of fortified wine types and the countries they’re from",
    "answer": "Sherry from Spain and Port from Portugal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is different about fortified wines?",
    "answer": "They had extra alcohol added to them"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does ABV stand for and how does it work?",
    "answer": "Alcohol by Volume. It’s the alcohol percentage in a given amount of liquid."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ABV in fortified wines?",
    "answer": "Between 15% and 22%."
  }
]